<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicolas Bourras</title>
    <link>https://nicolasb.fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nicolas Bourras</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 20:34:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nicolasb.fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/09/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 20:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/09/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : Vegan Apple Pie - Tasty
This took about 3 hours and a half to make (I was really slow). It&amp;rsquo;s enough for at least 5 people, and isn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to make.
Ingredients  310g all-purpose flour (and a little bit extra if the dough gets sticky) 400g + 1 tablespoon + 1 teaspoon organic sugar 1 + 1/2 teaspoon salt 225g vegan butter (cubed and chilled) 6 tablespoons of ice water 7 apples (I only used 5) 1 lemon, zested (I didn&amp;rsquo;t put this in) 1/2 lemon, juiced (I used a tablesppon of lemon juice) 5 tablespoons cornstarch 1 tablespoon coconut oil + 1 teaspoon 4 teaspoons cinnamon  Steps  In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar (a tablespoon) and salt (a teaspoon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Omelet</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/08/vegan-omelet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 12:35:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/08/vegan-omelet/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : La france végétalienne p.40 - Ed. L&amp;rsquo;Âge d&amp;rsquo;Homme
This took about one hour to make. It&amp;rsquo;s enough for 4 people, and is easy to make.
Ingredients  250g mushrooms (paris mushroom if possible) 50g chickpea flour 200g silken tofu 2 tablespoons of cornstarch 10cl water A half teaspoon of turmeric 2 tablespoons of olive oil Vegetal oil (for cooking) Salt Pepper The herbs you like (we used chive)  Steps  Clean the mushrooms, and make them sweat in an oiled pan for 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchis</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/07/gnocchis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 14:56:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/07/gnocchis/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : GNOCCHI VEGAN | Sain &amp;amp; Facile - Lloyd Lang
This took 2 hours and a half to prepare - altough I was slow at the beginning. It&amp;rsquo;s enough for 5 people.
Ingredients  1kg of potatoes 350g flour  Steps  Cook the potatoes using a steam cooker. Mash them in a large bowl, until you can&amp;rsquo;t find little potato chunks. Don&amp;rsquo;t mix for too long - It&amp;rsquo;ll make the gnocchis too elastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Bars</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/06/energy-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 16:12:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/06/energy-bars/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : Homemade Energy Bars - So Vegan
This took about 1h20 to prepare and bake, and produces around 10 energy bars (9 on the pictures, plus an extra one). It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to make.
Ingredients  85g oats 85g pumpkin seeds 150g almonds 80g raw buckwheat groats 70g raisins 70g dried cranberries 170g soft dried apricots 4 tablespoons of maple syrup 4 tablespoons of water  Steps  Preheat the oven to 180°c, and prepare a large (the original said 18x18cm) square tin with greaseproof paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/05/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 17:26:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/05/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : The perfect {vegan} banana bread - Valentina | The Baking Fairy
This took about an hour to prepare and bake, and is not too hard to make.
Ingredients  4 medium ripe bananas 60ml vegetable oil 60ml unsweetened nondairy milk 125g light brown sugar 2 teaspoons pure vanilla extract 260g unbleached all-purpose flour (in France : T80 flour) 1 teaspoon cinnamon 1 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 teaspoon salt A sliced banana, for topping  Steps  Preheat the oven at 175°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/04/pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 13:04:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/04/pizza/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Sources :
 EASY VEGAN PIZZA FROM SCRATCH - The Happy Pear Recettes vegan inratables - Les petits inratables. Ed. Larousse  The second source is for the dough, which we used instead of the one proposed in the video because it used ingredients not readily available in France.
This took about 1 hour and a half to make. It&amp;rsquo;s enough for 5 people, and is relatively easy to make - the dough is the hardest part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesto</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/04/pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 12:47:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/04/pesto/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Sources :
 Pesto Rosso - Cuisine Actuelle Spaghetti au pesto de basilic frais, 100% végétalien ou classique - La Fée Stéphanie  See the pizza recipes these were used on.
Pesto Rosso This took about 15min to make. It&amp;rsquo;s enough for at least 5 people, and is really easy to make.
Ingredients  100g (oil) dried tomatoes 25g pine nut A (small) clove of garlic Around 15 basil leaves (of all sizes) 7cl olive oil Pepper A teaspoon of tomato coulis  Steps  Carefully mix the tomatoes, tomato coulis, basil, garlic (peeled and minced), olive oil and pine nut in a blender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Baked Tofu Cubes</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/03/crispy-baked-tofu-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 13:00:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/03/crispy-baked-tofu-cubes/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : HOW TO COOK TOFU | Crispy baked tofu recipe - Clean &amp;amp; Delicious
This took about an hour and a half to make. It&amp;rsquo;s enough for 5 people, and is easy to make.
Ingredients  White rice Broccolis A big block of Tofu 1 tablespoon tamari 1 tablespoon avocado oil 1/4 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon pepper 1/2 teaspoon garlic powder 1 tablespoon corn starch 2 tablespoons teriyaki sauce Sriracha sauce (to taste) Sesame seeds  Steps  Preheat your oven to 200°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookies</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/02/cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 13:00:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/02/cookies/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : PERFECT Vegan Chocolate Chip Cookie Recipe - Pincha Pink Salt
This took about an half-hour to make, and is really easy.
Ingredients  260g flour 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/4 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon salt - the original recipe used 1 teaspoon of pink salt, but regular salt worked just fine 275g brown sugar 120ml oil 1 teaspoon vanilla 6 tablespoons plant milk Chocolate chips - we used 70% cocoa dark chocolate chopped in small pieces  Steps  Preheat oven at 175°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mushroom Pasta</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/01/creamy-mushroom-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 12:59:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/recipes/2020/06/01/creamy-mushroom-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Recipe Source : CREAMY MUSHROOM PASTA | OIL FREE &amp;amp; VEGAN - The Happy Pear
This took about 35min to make (I&amp;rsquo;m not good at cleaning mushrooms). It&amp;rsquo;s enough for 5 people, and is easy to make.
Ingredients  Two small red onions (we only used half of a large onion) 2 cloves of garlic A bit of vegetable stock 250g mushroom 3 tablespoons of tamari or soy sauce 250g of pasta (preferably wholemeal) 100g of cashew (preferably toasted cashews) 500ml of plant milk (no sugar milk) The juice of a half lemon or lime A teaspoon of salt A teaspoon of garlic powder Oregano or the herbs you prefer A red chili or anything you want (we didn&amp;rsquo;t put any)  Steps  Clean the mushrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://nicolasb.fr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolasb.fr/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Nicolas Bourras - a french student learning computer science at the Aix-Marseille university. I&amp;rsquo;ll be starting my fourth year in 2020.
I love cycling, programming, photography and more recently I started getting into cooking as well. I&amp;rsquo;m also vegan.
I mainly program in Rust these days, but I also regularly use Dart (with flutter) and python. I have experience with a fairly large number of languages, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesite to ask me about them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>